<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/linux/</link><description>Recent content in Linux on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my work life, I use a company-issued Windows 11 laptop. I genuinely enjoy working across all the major operating systems, from Linux and macOS to Windows itself—I’ve found that Windows has evolved in some really interesting ways, especially when it comes to Linux and Open Source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the very first things I do when setting up a new Windows system is make sure the &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about"&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL2)&lt;/a&gt; is installed and configured just the way I like it. I’ve been using WSL on a daily basis for years, and it’s become an essential part of my workflow, allowing me to run all the Linux tools I need in a familiar, integrated environment. Plus, it’s improved massively since I first tried it out on Windows 10 back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with GPTs: How I Built a Custom Assistant to Learn Linux</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/getting-started-with-gpts-how-i-built-a-custom-assistant-to-learn-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/getting-started-with-gpts-how-i-built-a-custom-assistant-to-learn-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2023 OpenAI introduced &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpts/"&gt;GPTs&lt;/a&gt; — custom versions of ChatGPT that anyone can create. These tailored assistants are designed to perform specific tasks, help with workflows, or simply provide a more personalised experience. In this post, I’ll explain what GPTs are, why they’re so useful, and how I created a custom GPT to help me learn Linux commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-are-gpts" id=what-are-gpts&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What Are GPTs?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-are-gpts" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPTs are specialised versions of ChatGPT that you can customise without needing to code. You can:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why You Shouldn’t Fear the Command Line</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For many new Linux users, the command line can feel intimidating—an unforgiving interface where one wrong move could wreak havoc. You might worry about typing the wrong command, forgetting what to do, or feeling like you need to memorise a dictionary’s worth of commands to get started. I understand this fear—I’ve been there. But the command line isn’t something to fear; it’s a powerful tool that, with a little practice, becomes second nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I Enjoy Using Linux</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed exploring different operating systems, but it&amp;rsquo;s Linux based systems that I enjoy the most. Over the years, I’ve come to appreciate its flexibility, control, and the sense of community it offers. Here are some of the reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-flexibility-and-customisation" id=1-flexibility-and-customisation&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;1. Flexibility and Customisation&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#1-flexibility-and-customisation" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Linux is its endless customisation options. Whether it’s tweaking the desktop environment, choosing your preferred package manager, or configuring system services, Linux offers unparalleled flexibility. I love that I can tailor the OS to fit my specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>