<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Networking on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/networking/</link><description>Recent content in Networking on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/networking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Taildrop: Secure File Sharing from Anywhere with Tailscale</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/taildrop-secure-file-sharing-from-anywhere-with-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/taildrop-secure-file-sharing-from-anywhere-with-tailscale/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tailscale has transformed the way I manage and access my homelab, providing seamless, secure connectivity between all my devices—wherever I am. In my previous post, &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/tailscale-homelab/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;How Tailscale Transformed Secure Access to My Homelab&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, I shared how Tailscale has become an essential part of my daily workflow, enabling remote access to servers, VMs, and services without exposing anything to the public internet. Today, I want to highlight another standout feature: Taildrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-taildrop" id=what-is-taildrop&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What is Taildrop?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-taildrop" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taildrop is a built-in feature of Tailscale that allows you to securely send files between any devices connected to your Tailnet. Taildrop transfers files over encrypted peer-to-peer connections, using the fastest available path. This makes it a great solution for sending sensitive or large files without third-party servers in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Tailscale Transformed Secure Access to My Homelab</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-tailscale-transformed-secure-access-to-my-homelab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-tailscale-transformed-secure-access-to-my-homelab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Connecting to services in a homelab can be a headache, especially when you want strong security without the hassle of port forwarding, firewall rules, or wrestling with certificates. Last year, I discovered &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/"&gt;Tailscale&lt;/a&gt; and introduced it to my &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/my-homelab-journey/"&gt;homelab&lt;/a&gt;. Tailscale has become my solution for secure, reliable, and zero-fuss access to certain services in my homelab—which I do not want to expose via the public internet. In this post, I’ll walk through what makes Tailscale so effective, how to set it up, and the best practices I’ve picked up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>