<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Docker on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/docker/</link><description>Recent content in Docker on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/docker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Moving from Portainer to Dockge</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/moving-from-portainer-to-dockge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/moving-from-portainer-to-dockge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I first dived into containerisation around 2020, eventually settling on a Virtual Private Server (VPS) setup where the focus shifted from managing hardware to mastering software and services. For a long time, the backbone of that software setup was Portainer. Portainer served as the graphical interface for managing the 20+ services I run in stacks on my VPS, handling everything from my reverse proxy to monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portainer is a robust GUI for managing containers and stacks, and I want to make it clear that my migration wasn&amp;rsquo;t driven by any failing on its part; it’s an excellent piece of kit. However, as my homelab evolved, I started looking for something that offered an even &lt;strong&gt;simpler and easier management experience&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted a dedicated tool that stripped back the complexity, allowing me to focus entirely on tweaking my Docker Compose files and stacks. That search led me straight to &lt;a href="https://dockge.kuma.pet/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dockge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Appreciation of Docker</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt; I finally set aside time to learn about containerisation. &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/get-started/"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; had been on my radar for a while, but I kept putting it off, convinced it was strictly developer territory. Determined to challenge that belief, I spun up a modest Virtual Private Server (VPS) with &lt;a href="https://contabo.com/en/"&gt;Contabo&lt;/a&gt; and embarked on a learn‑by‑doing journey, self‑hosting a handful of services. The concepts felt tricky at first, but I persevered, and as I grew comfortable with the Docker CLI, the hype began to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>