<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Approach to Personal Knowledge Management with Craft</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-approach-to-personal-knowledge-management-with-craft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-approach-to-personal-knowledge-management-with-craft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a technical professional and somebody who is constantly learning new skills, I’ve always taken time to document what I learn. I learned early on that relying on memory simply doesn’t scale, and documentation isn’t an afterthought for me, it’s a deliberate part of my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main reasons I document things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help future me remember how I did something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To share knowledge with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve worked in IT for any length of time, you’ll know how fast things move. A tool that feels essential today can be quietly deprecated tomorrow. In the age of AI, that pace has only accelerated. New frameworks, platforms, services, and workflows appear constantly, and the number of rabbit holes you can go down in any given tech stack is endless.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NotebookLM: The Ultimate Learning Assistant</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/notebooklm-the-ultimate-learning-assistant/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/notebooklm-the-ultimate-learning-assistant/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-evolving world of technology, staying ahead means constantly learning new skills, whether that’s mastering Linux, diving into Docker, or exploring a new cloud service. That hasn’t changed. Reading documentation, exploring blog posts, and watching tutorials are still essential parts of the learning process. What has changed for me is how I bring all of that material together. The tool I use to do that is &lt;a href="https://notebooklm.google.com/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NotebookLM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; which has slotted neatly into my learning toolkit, helping me research, retain, and make sense of the information.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Moving from Portainer to Dockge</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/moving-from-portainer-to-dockge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/moving-from-portainer-to-dockge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I first dived into containerisation around 2020, eventually settling on a Virtual Private Server (VPS) setup where the focus shifted from managing hardware to mastering software and services. For a long time, the backbone of that software setup was Portainer. Portainer served as the graphical interface for managing the 20+ services I run in stacks on my VPS, handling everything from my reverse proxy to monitoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portainer is a robust GUI for managing containers and stacks, and I want to make it clear that my migration wasn&amp;rsquo;t driven by any failing on its part; it’s an excellent piece of kit. However, as my homelab evolved, I started looking for something that offered an even &lt;strong&gt;simpler and easier management experience&lt;/strong&gt;. I wanted a dedicated tool that stripped back the complexity, allowing me to focus entirely on tweaking my Docker Compose files and stacks. That search led me straight to &lt;a href="https://dockge.kuma.pet/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dockge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Glance: My Favourite Homelab Dashboard</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/glance-my-favourite-homelab-dashboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/glance-my-favourite-homelab-dashboard/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently started using &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/glanceapp/glance"&gt;Glance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as the primary dashboard for my homelab, and it has quickly become one of my most-used tools. Glance allows me to monitor all my Docker containers, network devices, and services at a glance (pun intended), all within a clean, minimalist interface. It’s lightweight, fast, and extremely customisable, giving me real-time visibility into my entire environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-glance" id=what-is-glance&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What Is Glance?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-glance" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Glance is a self-hosted dashboard that you can configure entirely through a simple YAML file. It’s designed for speed, clarity, and ease of maintenance while giving you total control over layout and content. You can display container statuses, system metrics, bookmarks, RSS feeds, or even pull live data from APIs. It offers a clean, centralised view. of the information that matters most, keeping everything organised and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Discovering n8n: The Workflow Automation Platform</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/discovering-n8n-the-workflow-automation-platform/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/discovering-n8n-the-workflow-automation-platform/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Automation has always fascinated me for its ability to simplify complex processes and free up time for creative work. That curiosity naturally led me to explore new tools and that’s how I discovered &lt;strong&gt;n8n&lt;/strong&gt;, a workflow automation platform that has quickly become one of my favourite tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I kept seeing videos and articles about n8n pop up and it was one of those tools that never quite left my “must-try” list. As someone who’s passionate about automation, I was curious to see what made it stand out. Once I started digging deeper, I quickly realised how powerful and flexible it was.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Cloud Homelab Setup</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-cloud-homelab-setup/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-cloud-homelab-setup/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When I first started exploring the world of homelabs, I thought it had to involve racks of hardware, blinking lights, and endless tinkering. I even wrote about my early experiments &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/my-homelab-journey/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. At that time, I repurposed an old desktop PC and dived head-first into virtualisation with Proxmox, containers, and self-hosted services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fun, but I quickly realised that what really interested me wasn’t the hardware - it was the &lt;strong&gt;software and services&lt;/strong&gt;. I loved spinning up tools, learning how they worked, and making them accessible on my own terms. The hardware side, while interesting, left me feeling stuck in “decision paralysis”, what’s the perfect setup? What hardware should I buy next? Should I build a Kubernetes cluster? Instead of enjoying the process, I was constantly second-guessing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building My Own Prompt Generator GPT</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/building-my-own-prompt-generator-gpt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/building-my-own-prompt-generator-gpt/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I love using &lt;a href="https://help.openai.com/en/articles/10169521-projects-in-chatgpt"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; to organise my chats. Aside from the organisational aspects of Projects, it is such a powerful way to interact with ChatGPT because it allows you to add custom instructions and files specifically related to the project. This is very important as it provides context for the model, and context is key when interacting with Large Language Models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend, I sat here trying to create the perfect custom project instructions and, despite my best efforts, I was not entirely satisfied with the output. I realised I was spending way too much time manually drafting custom instructions for my ChatGPT Projects. I kept running into the same problem: &lt;strong&gt;prompt structure&lt;/strong&gt;. Then the penny dropped: I realised I could just use ChatGPT to help me build this, and so I built a &lt;strong&gt;Prompt Generator GPT&lt;/strong&gt;. I worked iteratively with GPT-5, asking the model to ask me clarifying questions to help me design a &lt;strong&gt;prompt&lt;/strong&gt; which will allow me to build project instructions for a wide range of subjects.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I Use Perplexity to Stay Informed and Learn New Skills</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-i-use-perplexity-to-stay-informed-and-learn-new-skills/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-i-use-perplexity-to-stay-informed-and-learn-new-skills/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If there’s one AI tool I reach for every day without fail, it’s &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai"&gt;Perplexity&lt;/a&gt;. It has become my go-to assistant for staying up to date with the latest news and exploring new topics. I wanted to share how I use it, why I keep coming back to it, and a few features I think are genuinely worth exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="my-two-main-use-cases-news-and-learning" id=my-two-main-use-cases-news-and-learning&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;My Two Main Use Cases: News and Learning&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#my-two-main-use-cases-news-and-learning" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use Perplexity primarily in two ways:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tailscale Saves the Day</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/tailscale-saves-the-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/tailscale-saves-the-day/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/tailscale-homelab/"&gt;previous post about Tailscale&lt;/a&gt;, I covered what Tailscale is and why it’s become a staple in my homelab toolkit. Today, I want to share a real-world example of just how handy it can be—specifically, how it helped me retrieve personal documents from my homelab while sat on a train, armed with nothing more than my iPhone and a 5G connection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-situation-needing-remote-access-on-the-go" id=the-situation-needing-remote-access-on-the-go&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;The Situation: Needing Remote Access on the Go&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#the-situation-needing-remote-access-on-the-go" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been there: you need a file, but it’s tucked away on your home network, and you’re nowhere near your desk. For me, this happened while I was on a train, miles away from home. The documents I needed were only accessible from my local network—or so I thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Managing Dotfiles the Smart Way with Chezmoi</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/managing-dotfiles-the-smart-way-with-chezmoi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/managing-dotfiles-the-smart-way-with-chezmoi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Managing configuration files across multiple systems can quickly become a mess. From terminal preferences to shell settings, we all have a finely-tuned setup that we rely on day-to-day. But how do you keep those settings consistent across machines? And how do you avoid the chaos of losing them after a reinstall?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where a tool like &lt;a href="https://www.chezmoi.io/"&gt;Chezmoi&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-chezmoi" id=what-is-chezmoi&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What is Chezmoi?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-chezmoi" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chezmoi is a powerful dotfile manager designed to track, version, and securely deploy your configuration files across multiple operating systems. It helps you manage configuration files such as &lt;code&gt;~/.zshrc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/.gitconfig&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/.config/&lt;/code&gt; and more — all with a simple Git workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Taildrop: Secure File Sharing from Anywhere with Tailscale</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/taildrop-secure-file-sharing-from-anywhere-with-tailscale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/taildrop-secure-file-sharing-from-anywhere-with-tailscale/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tailscale has transformed the way I manage and access my homelab, providing seamless, secure connectivity between all my devices—wherever I am. In my previous post, &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/tailscale-homelab/"&gt;&amp;ldquo;How Tailscale Transformed Secure Access to My Homelab&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, I shared how Tailscale has become an essential part of my daily workflow, enabling remote access to servers, VMs, and services without exposing anything to the public internet. Today, I want to highlight another standout feature: Taildrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-taildrop" id=what-is-taildrop&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What is Taildrop?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-taildrop" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taildrop is a built-in feature of Tailscale that allows you to securely send files between any devices connected to your Tailnet. Taildrop transfers files over encrypted peer-to-peer connections, using the fastest available path. This makes it a great solution for sending sensitive or large files without third-party servers in the middle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Tailscale Transformed Secure Access to My Homelab</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-tailscale-transformed-secure-access-to-my-homelab/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-tailscale-transformed-secure-access-to-my-homelab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Connecting to services in a homelab can be a headache, especially when you want strong security without the hassle of port forwarding, firewall rules, or wrestling with certificates. Last year, I discovered &lt;a href="https://tailscale.com/"&gt;Tailscale&lt;/a&gt; and introduced it to my &lt;a href="https://blog.autonate.dev/posts/my-homelab-journey/"&gt;homelab&lt;/a&gt;. Tailscale has become my solution for secure, reliable, and zero-fuss access to certain services in my homelab—which I do not want to expose via the public internet. In this post, I’ll walk through what makes Tailscale so effective, how to set it up, and the best practices I’ve picked up along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my work life, I use a company-issued Windows 11 laptop. I genuinely enjoy working across all the major operating systems, from Linux and macOS to Windows itself—I’ve found that Windows has evolved in some really interesting ways, especially when it comes to Linux and Open Source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the very first things I do when setting up a new Windows system is make sure the &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about"&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL2)&lt;/a&gt; is installed and configured just the way I like it. I’ve been using WSL on a daily basis for years, and it’s become an essential part of my workflow, allowing me to run all the Linux tools I need in a familiar, integrated environment. Plus, it’s improved massively since I first tried it out on Windows 10 back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understanding APIs: A Beginner-Friendly Guide</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/understanding-apis-a-beginner-friendly-guide/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/understanding-apis-a-beginner-friendly-guide/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-is-an-api" id=what-is-an-api&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What is an API?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-an-api" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;APIs, short for Application Programming Interfaces, are tools that allow software applications to communicate with each other. They define a set of rules and protocols that enable developers to access features or data from another service without needing to understand or modify the underlying code. Think of them as messengers that deliver your request to another service and return the response back to you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Appreciation of Docker</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt; I finally set aside time to learn about containerisation. &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/get-started/"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; had been on my radar for a while, but I kept putting it off, convinced it was strictly developer territory. Determined to challenge that belief, I spun up a modest Virtual Private Server (VPS) with &lt;a href="https://contabo.com/en/"&gt;Contabo&lt;/a&gt; and embarked on a learn‑by‑doing journey, self‑hosting a handful of services. The concepts felt tricky at first, but I persevered, and as I grew comfortable with the Docker CLI, the hype began to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Perplexity Has Replaced Search Engines for Everyday Knowledge</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-perplexity-has-replaced-search-engines-for-everyday-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/how-perplexity-has-replaced-search-engines-for-everyday-knowledge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Like many people, my daily routine involves a search engine. Whether it is a quick fact, the latest headlines, or a deep dive into a new topic, search engines have always been the gateway to discovery. For me, that changed in 2023, when I discovered &lt;a href="https://www.perplexity.ai"&gt;Perplexity&lt;/a&gt;—an AI-powered research tool that’s quietly revolutionised how I find and use information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="the-evolution-of-everyday-search" id=the-evolution-of-everyday-search&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;The Evolution of Everyday Search&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#the-evolution-of-everyday-search" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional search engines have always been about links. Type a query, get a list of websites, and hope the answer is buried somewhere on page one. Perplexity takes a different approach: it delivers direct, well-sourced answers to your questions, right up front. No more hopping between tabs or skimming articles for a single fact. The experience is more like chatting with a knowledgeable assistant than using a search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting Started with GPTs: How I Built a Custom Assistant to Learn Linux</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/getting-started-with-gpts-how-i-built-a-custom-assistant-to-learn-linux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/getting-started-with-gpts-how-i-built-a-custom-assistant-to-learn-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2023 OpenAI introduced &lt;a href="https://openai.com/index/introducing-gpts/"&gt;GPTs&lt;/a&gt; — custom versions of ChatGPT that anyone can create. These tailored assistants are designed to perform specific tasks, help with workflows, or simply provide a more personalised experience. In this post, I’ll explain what GPTs are, why they’re so useful, and how I created a custom GPT to help me learn Linux commands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-are-gpts" id=what-are-gpts&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What Are GPTs?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-are-gpts" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPTs are specialised versions of ChatGPT that you can customise without needing to code. You can:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Discovering Ollama: Running Open Source LLMs Locally</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/discovering-ollama-running-open-source-llms-locally/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/discovering-ollama-running-open-source-llms-locally/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered &lt;strong&gt;Ollama&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a href="https://ollama.com/"&gt;ollama.com&lt;/a&gt;), a platform that allows you to run open-source Large Language Models (LLMs) directly on your local machine. As someone with an M1 Pro MacBook Pro, I was intrigued by the idea of leveraging my hardware to run advanced AI models privately. After exploring Ollama and experimenting with open-source models like &lt;strong&gt;Llama&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Mistral&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Phi&lt;/strong&gt;, I’ve been amazed at the speed and quality these models deliver—especially considering they’re running locally.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understanding Prompt Engineering: The Art of Communicating with LLMs</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/understanding-prompt-engineering-the-art-of-communicating-with-llms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/understanding-prompt-engineering-the-art-of-communicating-with-llms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Prompt engineering is a crucial skill in today’s AI-driven world. At its core, it’s the process of designing and optimising prompts to interact effectively with natural language processing (NLP) models like ChatGPT. Crafting a good prompt is an art and a science, and when done well, it can drastically improve the quality of responses from AI systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re writing prompts for work, learning, or creative projects, understanding the basics of prompt engineering can make your interactions with AI more productive and rewarding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The AI Explosion: How It’s Changing the Way We Work and Live</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/the-ai-explosion-how-its-changing-the-way-we-work-and-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/the-ai-explosion-how-its-changing-the-way-we-work-and-live/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We’re living in the middle of an AI revolution. The rapid advancements in artificial intelligence feel like the dawn of a new era—much like how the internet and the World Wide Web transformed the way we live, communicate, and work. In just a few short years, AI has gone from a buzzword to a daily tool many of us use, and the pace of progress shows no signs of slowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Homelab Journey...So Far</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-homelab-journey...so-far/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-homelab-journey...so-far/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Diving into the world of Linux naturally led me to discover the vibrant homelab community. What began as casual curiosity soon became a genuine fascination, fuelled by countless YouTube videos showcasing everything from compact, single-board computers to sprawling, business-grade server racks. The creativity and technical depth on display resonated with my own desire to experiment and learn by doing. But as I watched, a set of questions began to form: Did I actually need a homelab? What would I use it for? Did it require a significant investment in hardware? And, crucially, how should I even begin?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Apple Shortcuts</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-apple-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-apple-shortcuts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When people think of iPhones, they often picture sleek hardware and user-friendly software. Of course, if you’re team Android, that’s perfectly fine—there’s no room for tribalism here. But I digress. Back to the topic at hand: one of iOS’s most underrated features is hiding in plain sight—Apple Shortcuts. This powerful app allows you to automate tasks, saving time and effort on repetitive actions. Yet despite its incredible potential, many iPhone users either tuck it away in a folder or remove it entirely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First Impressions of GPT-4</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/first-impressions-of-gpt-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/first-impressions-of-gpt-4/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It’s only been a few weeks since OpenAI released GPT-4, and I’ve already been putting it to work. As a ChatGPT Plus subscriber, I’ve gained access to this new model, albeit with frustratingly low rate limits that I hope will improve in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite that, the excitement I am feeling is real. GPT-4 feels like a gear shift, a real turning point, not just in AI capability, but in how I personally approach learning. I’ve been experimenting with Large Language Models (LLMs) for some time now, mainly to augment my learning around technical subjects. With GPT-4, that approach feels more powerful than ever.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Documentation Is My Second Brain</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-documentation-is-my-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-documentation-is-my-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced world of technology, keeping up with new tools, concepts, and workflows can feel overwhelming. That’s why I rely heavily on documentation—it’s not just a task; it’s a mindset. Documentation serves as my &lt;strong&gt;second brain&lt;/strong&gt;, a system I can rely on to store, organise, and retrieve the knowledge I’ve accumulated over time. It helps me stay sharp, grow professionally, and contribute to others’ understanding. Here’s why it’s so important to me and how I approach it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Git</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-git/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been diving deeper into Git recently, using it daily in my current role compared to just every other day in previous positions. While I’ve been comfortable with the core Git commands for a while, my current role has pushed me to explore more advanced Git concepts and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be useful to compile this guide as a reference, both for myself and for anyone else looking to sharpen their Git skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I Still Use RSS to Stay Informed</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-still-use-rss-to-stay-informed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-still-use-rss-to-stay-informed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of social media algorithms, personalised feeds, and endless scrolling, it might seem odd to rely on an older technology like RSS to stay informed. But for me, RSS remains one of the best ways to stay on top of my interests without the noise and distractions of modern platforms. Here&amp;rsquo;s why I still use RSS after all these years, how it helps me cut through the clutter, and why I prefer it over social media algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why You Shouldn’t Fear the Command Line</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For many new Linux users, the command line can feel intimidating—an unforgiving interface where one wrong move could wreak havoc. You might worry about typing the wrong command, forgetting what to do, or feeling like you need to memorise a dictionary’s worth of commands to get started. I understand this fear—I’ve been there. But the command line isn’t something to fear; it’s a powerful tool that, with a little practice, becomes second nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I Enjoy Using Linux</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed exploring different operating systems, but it&amp;rsquo;s Linux based systems that I enjoy the most. Over the years, I’ve come to appreciate its flexibility, control, and the sense of community it offers. Here are some of the reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-flexibility-and-customisation" id=1-flexibility-and-customisation&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;1. Flexibility and Customisation&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#1-flexibility-and-customisation" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Linux is its endless customisation options. Whether it’s tweaking the desktop environment, choosing your preferred package manager, or configuring system services, Linux offers unparalleled flexibility. I love that I can tailor the OS to fit my specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Intro</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/intro/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/intro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;👋🏻 Hello, I am Nathan, a technical professional from the UK with an interest in &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;System Administration&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;DevOps&lt;/strong&gt;. Welcome to my personal blog and knowledge repository. This blog is a space where I share my journey through the ever-changing landscape of technology. Documenting software recommendations, useful automations, interesting developments in AI, or deep dives into Linux commands, you&amp;rsquo;ll find it all here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this blog is to build a personal knowledge repository by sharing guides, tutorials, and insights across various technical subjects which I explore. My goal is to create a practical repository of knowledge that not only helps me retain what I learn but also serves as a guide for anyone else who may find the information useful. This blog will contain recommendations, guides, tutorials, and technical notes based on real-world experiences.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>