<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cli on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/cli/</link><description>Recent content in Cli on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/cli/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing Dotfiles the Smart Way with Chezmoi</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/managing-dotfiles-the-smart-way-with-chezmoi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/managing-dotfiles-the-smart-way-with-chezmoi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Managing configuration files across multiple systems can quickly become a mess. From terminal preferences to shell settings, we all have a finely-tuned setup that we rely on day-to-day. But how do you keep those settings consistent across machines? And how do you avoid the chaos of losing them after a reinstall?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s where a tool like &lt;a href="https://www.chezmoi.io/"&gt;Chezmoi&lt;/a&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-chezmoi" id=what-is-chezmoi&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;What is Chezmoi?&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#what-is-chezmoi" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chezmoi is a powerful dotfile manager designed to track, version, and securely deploy your configuration files across multiple operating systems. It helps you manage configuration files such as &lt;code&gt;~/.zshrc&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/.gitconfig&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;~/.config/&lt;/code&gt; and more — all with a simple Git workflow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring the Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL)</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/exploring-the-windows-subsystem-for-linux-wsl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my work life, I use a company-issued Windows 11 laptop. I genuinely enjoy working across all the major operating systems, from Linux and macOS to Windows itself—I’ve found that Windows has evolved in some really interesting ways, especially when it comes to Linux and Open Source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the very first things I do when setting up a new Windows system is make sure the &lt;a href="https://learn.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/wsl/about"&gt;Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL2)&lt;/a&gt; is installed and configured just the way I like it. I’ve been using WSL on a daily basis for years, and it’s become an essential part of my workflow, allowing me to run all the Linux tools I need in a familiar, integrated environment. Plus, it’s improved massively since I first tried it out on Windows 10 back in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Appreciation of Docker</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-appreciation-of-docker/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Back in &lt;strong&gt;2020&lt;/strong&gt; I finally set aside time to learn about containerisation. &lt;a href="https://www.docker.com/get-started/"&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt; had been on my radar for a while, but I kept putting it off, convinced it was strictly developer territory. Determined to challenge that belief, I spun up a modest Virtual Private Server (VPS) with &lt;a href="https://contabo.com/en/"&gt;Contabo&lt;/a&gt; and embarked on a learn‑by‑doing journey, self‑hosting a handful of services. The concepts felt tricky at first, but I persevered, and as I grew comfortable with the Docker CLI, the hype began to make sense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>An Introduction to Git</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-git/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/an-introduction-to-git/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been diving deeper into Git recently, using it daily in my current role compared to just every other day in previous positions. While I’ve been comfortable with the core Git commands for a while, my current role has pushed me to explore more advanced Git concepts and techniques.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it would be useful to compile this guide as a reference, both for myself and for anyone else looking to sharpen their Git skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why You Shouldn’t Fear the Command Line</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-you-shouldnt-fear-the-command-line/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For many new Linux users, the command line can feel intimidating—an unforgiving interface where one wrong move could wreak havoc. You might worry about typing the wrong command, forgetting what to do, or feeling like you need to memorise a dictionary’s worth of commands to get started. I understand this fear—I’ve been there. But the command line isn’t something to fear; it’s a powerful tool that, with a little practice, becomes second nature.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I Enjoy Using Linux</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-enjoy-using-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always enjoyed exploring different operating systems, but it&amp;rsquo;s Linux based systems that I enjoy the most. Over the years, I’ve come to appreciate its flexibility, control, and the sense of community it offers. Here are some of the reasons why:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-flexibility-and-customisation" id=1-flexibility-and-customisation&gt;
 
 &lt;span class="me-2"&gt;1. Flexibility and Customisation&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;a href="#1-flexibility-and-customisation" class="anchor text-muted"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-hashtag"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the standout features of Linux is its endless customisation options. Whether it’s tweaking the desktop environment, choosing your preferred package manager, or configuring system services, Linux offers unparalleled flexibility. I love that I can tailor the OS to fit my specific needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>