<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Productivity on autonate</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/productivity/</link><description>Recent content in Productivity on autonate</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.autonate.dev/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Approach to Personal Knowledge Management with Craft</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-approach-to-personal-knowledge-management-with-craft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/my-approach-to-personal-knowledge-management-with-craft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As a technical professional and somebody who is constantly learning new skills, I’ve always taken time to document what I learn. I learned early on that relying on memory simply doesn’t scale, and documentation isn’t an afterthought for me, it’s a deliberate part of my workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main reasons I document things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To help future me remember how I did something&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To share knowledge with others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve worked in IT for any length of time, you’ll know how fast things move. A tool that feels essential today can be quietly deprecated tomorrow. In the age of AI, that pace has only accelerated. New frameworks, platforms, services, and workflows appear constantly, and the number of rabbit holes you can go down in any given tech stack is endless.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Documentation Is My Second Brain</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-documentation-is-my-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-documentation-is-my-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the fast-paced world of technology, keeping up with new tools, concepts, and workflows can feel overwhelming. That’s why I rely heavily on documentation—it’s not just a task; it’s a mindset. Documentation serves as my &lt;strong&gt;second brain&lt;/strong&gt;, a system I can rely on to store, organise, and retrieve the knowledge I’ve accumulated over time. It helps me stay sharp, grow professionally, and contribute to others’ understanding. Here’s why it’s so important to me and how I approach it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why I Still Use RSS to Stay Informed</title><link>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-still-use-rss-to-stay-informed/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.autonate.dev/post/why-i-still-use-rss-to-stay-informed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of social media algorithms, personalised feeds, and endless scrolling, it might seem odd to rely on an older technology like RSS to stay informed. But for me, RSS remains one of the best ways to stay on top of my interests without the noise and distractions of modern platforms. Here&amp;rsquo;s why I still use RSS after all these years, how it helps me cut through the clutter, and why I prefer it over social media algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>